Kathleen N. Wong

wongkathleen@berkeley.edu | linkedin.com/in/kathleen-wong | kathuhlee.github.io/ | Oakland, CA

PROFESSIONAL | PASSIONATE | SELF-STARTER

OBJECTIVE

An experienced and highly motivated Junior Full Stack Developer and Scrum Master with a strong passion for learning and building websites to provide great user experiences. Constantly seeking new challenges in all of life's facets to break baselines via full marathons and optimized code with seamless design. Passionate, high tolerance for stress and patient individual with 7+ years in education and 11+ years of community service working with diverse populations of all ages and backgrounds. Self-starting, strong attention to detail and in-depth experience in multitasking, and organizing in a fast-paced environment. Represented USA at Dragon Boat World Championships & mentor to students learning code.

TECHNICAL SKILLS & CERTIFICATIONS

- Java
- JavaScript ES6+
- HTML5
- CSS3 (BEM)
- Spring Boot
- Spring Data JPA

- Spring Security (JWT)
- Bootstrap
- REST API's
- SQL
- Unit Testing (JUnit, Mockito)
- SOLID OOP Principles
- Dependencies Injection
- Git / Github
- React(+hooks)
- Npm
- Agile
- Scrum

AWS Certified Developer Associate in progress
AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner awarded December 2022
SAFe for Teams Practitioner awarded December 2022
W3Schools JavaScript Certification awarded November 2022

EDUCATION

University of California, Berkeley | Bachelor of Arts Degree in Political Science, awarded in December 2016

EXPERIENCE

TEKsystems | Junior Full Stack Developer & Scrum Master | August 2022 - present

- Engage in all the parts of the Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC) including analysis, design, coding, testing, debugging and documenting
- Create software using industry standards and best practices and employ test driven design in a highly collaborative team
- Work with the lead developer to ensure full comprehension of the user stories, acceptance criteria and technical implementation to reach Definition of Ready (DoR) to Definition of Done (DoD)
- · Coach and manage projects for two teams to higher levels of maturity by improving their process using agile practices
- Facilitate ceremonies, discussion, decision making and conflict resolution across 2 cross-functional teams

Generation Junior Full Stack Java Developer Program | Training Participant | August 2022 - December 2022

- Practice hands-on practical application in a 16-week, 460+ hour Junior Full Stack Java Developer program
- Deploy the technologies involved in creating full stack web applications with Java using Spring Boot Framework, Javascript, HTML5, CSS3
- Implement unit tests and deploy the application to Heroku

TEKsystems Full Stack Boot Camp | Student Intern | May 2022 - August 2022

- Engineer scalable, responsive, multi-platform and SEO friendly websites for multiple clients using HTML5, CSS3+ BEM, JavaScript ES6+, Java, object-oriented design, test-driven development, SOLID principles and React best practices
- Connect to backend API's through CRUD HTTP requests using Spring Boot
- Collaborate within a software development team in projects and exemplify agile principles
- Utilize Git and GitHub to create, clone, push/pull, revert, reset, check, and run base commands
- Code in Java and communicate the principles of object-oriented programming
- Use advanced concepts to develop backend code to handle collections and database interactions
- Connect to backend API's through CRUD HTTP requests using Spring Boot